# Karl Roush

karl.roush@gmail.com • 908-415-9479 • US Citizen



# Overview

Complete GitHub Research Repos

Eagle Scout, BS/MS Aerospace Engineering; research experience with jet engine design & drones, hands-on shop experience through various research projects and competitive racing teams. Interest in designing/increasing efficiency of aerospace systems- esp. propulsion. Additional interests in cybersecurity et. al

### Education

Aug 2017 - May 2020

Aug 2020 - Dec 2021

Georgia Institute of Technology, BS Aerospace Engineering Summer 2018 Oxford Program, ΣΓΤ Honor society

GPA: 3.80, Graduated with Highest Honors

Georgia Institute of Technology, MS Aerospace Engineering BS/MS AE Honors program

# **Experience**

#### Fabrication Lead- Aerospace Systems Design Laboratory

Aug 2018 - Present

Air Force Research Lab: Aerospace Propulsion Outreach Program

- -AFRL engineering design competition: increased the thrust/weight ratio of a small gas turbine engine by 13.67%
- -Currently working on solutions to wind-milling and small scale thrust vectoring

#### **UTSR Gas Turbine Industrial Fellowship**

May 2019 - Aug 2019

Research Fellow: Southwest Research Institute, Department of Energy Office of Fossil Energy

- -Determined viability of hybrid cycle UAVs for surveillance missions & created an NPSS tool for subsequent mission analysis
- -Designed and built laser PIV system for <10% of quoted industry cost for low speed turbulence testing
- -Standardized NPSS unit conversions for international use, streamlined data collection of drag testing (65% time reduction)

#### **Competitive Innovation Consultant**

May 2017 - Present

MindSumo: A competitive problem-solving platform; Awarded wins from AAA, Mozilla, NASA, Siemens, GSK, et. al

-Ranked in the top 5 of 350,000+ solvers, Chosen as a winner for 93% of competitions (Mindsumo All-Star average= 20%)

# **Projects**

#### **Engine Component Preliminary Design**

Aug. 2019- Present

Designed & optimized: compressor, combustor, and turbine of a small, single spool turbojet engine; evaluated off-design performance

#### Electrical Engineering/CS Student Researcher: Rutgers WINLAB

Sept 2016- Aug 2017

EE/CS robotics-based projects: 3D Spectrum Sensing Map via Drone Mounted Receiver, Drone Gesture Based Control, Smart Electronic Bicycle

# Notable Awards/Certificates

#### Eagle Scout Rank Award, Bronze Palm and Gold Palm

Mar 2015

Awarded Bronze Palm in October 2015, Gold Palm September 2016

#### Wells Fargo Campus Analytics Challenge Winner (Two Times)

Dec 2018, 2019

Machine learning analytics challenge, 2018= model for minimizing carbon footprint, 2019= Topic generation based on NASA datasets

#### International Best Use of Data- NASA Space Apps Hackathon

Sept 2016

First Place Overall (Project: EvaS)- Space Apps Next Gen NYC Hackathon Challenge

Developed a search for Extra-Vehicular Activities via NASA's public data in HTML/CSS and JavaScript over the course of ~14 hours

#### Skills and Certifications

Programs: NPSS, SolidWorks, MATLAB, Git

Languages: Python, C++, HTML/CSS, JavaScript

Machine shop certified

Mill, lathe, band saw, drill press, sanders

**Class 4 Laser Safety Certified** Laser and Lab Safety Training

German, Latin ILR Level 2 fluency

# Clubs and Activities

**American Institute of Aeronautics & Astronautics** 

**GreyHat, Information Security** 

**GT Hytech Racing (FSAE)** 

Chair, GT Student Chapter

Vice President

Aero/Composites sub-team

#### **Relevant Coursework**

Propulsion System Design

Adv. Aircraft Propulsion **Optimization Algorithms**  Aircraft Design

Flight Dynamics & Controls

# Personal Interests

Rapid Prototyping

Metal work & painting

Information security

Machine learning

Service via *Eagles@GT*